A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Policy Office, Records, 2002-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Library of Virginia
- III. Legislative Files, 2006-2009 (accession 44701)., Extent: 33.60 cubic feet (96 boxes). (Box 49-141, 170-172)
  - 2009 Regular Session
    - House of Delegates
      - HB 2348 (09) Fiduciaries distributing intangible personal property to file informative tax returns; repealed (Box 128, Folder 24)
      - HB 2349 (09) Richmond Metropolitan Authority; created (Box 128, Folder 25)
      - HB 2350 (09) Transportation of troops by railroad; repeals obsolete section (Box 128, Folder 26)
      - HB 2351 (09) Natural Resources Commitment Fund; Dept. of Conservation, etc., to provide annual funding needed (Box 128, Folder 27)
      - HB 2352 (09) Donation of prescription medication; clarifies liability of pharmaceutical manufacturers (Box 128, Folder 28)
      - HB 2353 (09) School for Deaf and Blind; re-establishes Board of Visitors thereof (Box 128, Folder 29)
      - HB 2358 (09) Triggerman rule; redefinition thereof, penalty (Box 128, Folder 30)
      - HB 2360 (09) Retail Sales and Use Tax; exempts fabrication of animal meat (Box 128, Folder 31)
      - HB 2362 (09) Drug offenses; person convicted of second offense would be a felon if committed in State (Box 128, Folder 32)
      - HB 2364 (09) Dangerous or vicious dog; court may order owner to pay restitution for damages to injured person (Box 128, Folder 33)
      - HB 2366 (09) Charter; Town of Strasburg (Box 128, Folder 34)
      - HB 2371 (09) Rates; SCC to conduct proceeding relating thereto for certain sales of electric power to customers (Box 128, Folder 35)
      - HB 2378 (09) Noncorporate entities; minimum tax is imposed on telecommunications and electric suppliers (Box 128, Folder 36)
      - HB 2391 (09) Foreign service; search warrant for electronic communications (Box 128, Folder 37)
      - HB 2393 (09) Animal control officers; inclusion thereof in classification of law-enforcement officers (Box 128, Folder 38)
      - HB 2396 (09) Advance medical directives; revises Health Care Decisions Act to clarify process (Box 128, Folder 39)
      - HB 2397 (09) Child pornography; venue for prosecution where unlawful act thereof is produced, stored, etc. (Box 128, Folder 40)
      - HB 2400 (09) Criminal sexual assault; establishment of a multidisciplinary response thereto (Box 128, Folder 41)
      - HB 2401 (09) Fallen Heroes Memorial Bridge, etc.; designating as memorial bridges (Box 129, Folder 1)
      - HB 2402 (09) Identity theft; obtaining money, credit, etc. without authorization is prohibited under statutes (Box 129, Folder 2)
      - HB 2403 (09) Criminal Injuries Compensation Fund; electronic filing of claims (Box 129, Folder 3)
      - HB 2405 (09) Health Professions, Department of; may release information for determining shortage designations (Box 129, Folder 4)
      - HB 2406 (09) School records; may be received as evidence in cases involving custody of students, etc. (Box 129, Folder 5)
      - HB 2407 (09) Health Practitioners' Intervention Program; revisions, changes name (Box 129, Folder 6)
      - HB 2408 (09) Community development authorities; makes comprehensive changes to provisions related thereto (Box 129, Folder 7)
      - HB 2409 (09) Holocaust education; Board of Education to establish objectives therefor (Box 129, Folder 8)
      - HB 2410 (09) Richmond Ambulance Authority; adds board thereof to entities that local government may appoint (Box 129, Folder 9)
      - HB 2413 (09) Craney Island Disposal Area; constructing marine terminal with dredge material is authorized (Box 129, Folder 10)
      - HB 2415 (09) Technology Research Fund; robotics and unmanned vehicle systems, etc., to eligible research programs (Box 129, Folder 11)
      - HB 2417 (09) Covenants regarding solar power; clarifies community associations may prohibit or restrict (Box 129, Folder 12)
      - HB 2422 (09) Voting equipment; locality that acquired DREs prior to 7-1-07 may temporarily conduct election (Box 129, Folder 13)
      - HB 2423 (09) Broadband Advisory Council; established (Box 129, Folder 14)
      - HB 2424 (09) Graffiti; restitution for abatement costs (Box 129, Folder 15)
      - HB 2425 (09) Highways, primary and secondary; transfer roads, bridges, etc., therefrom to local system of roads (Box 129, Folder 16)
      - HB 2426 (09) Government Data Collection and Dissemination Practices Act; extends implementation of prohibition (Box 129, Folder 17)
      - HB 2427 (09) Protection of Social Security Numbers Act; first five digits to be confidential from disclosure (Box 129, Folder 18)
      - HB 2428 (09) Distribution of handbills, etc. on highways; grants Loudoun County power to regulate (Box 129, Folder 19)
      - HB 2429 (09) Land development plans; adds Town of Leesburg to localities that may develop procedure for review (Box 129, Folder 20)
      - HB 2430 (09) Electronic delivery of insurance notices; authorizes insurers to electronically transmit (Box 129, Folder 21)
      - HB 2432 (09) Asbestos, Lead, and Home Inspectors, Board for; regulation of lead-based paint renovation, etc. (Box 129, Folder 22)
      - HB 2433 (09) Eastern Virginia Medical School; alters manner in which Board of Visitors is appointed (Box 129, Folder 23)
      - HB 2434 (09) Corporations; allows certain to be represented by an officer before general district courts (Box 129, Folder 24)
      - HB 2435 (09) Uniform Principal and Income Act; trustee required to demand certain distributions if requested (Box 129, Folder 25)
      - HB 2437 (09) Income tax, corporate; apportionment for manufacturers (Box 129, Folder 26)
      - HB 2441 (09) Corrections, Department of; powers and duties of Director (Box 129, Folder 27)
      - HB 2442 (09) Investment Performance Grants; raises per project amount thereof (Box 129, Folder 28)
      - HB 2445 (09) Stock and Nonstock Corporation Acts; conforms provisions and makes technical amendments (Box 129, Folder 29)
      - HB 2446 (09) Motor fuels and lubricating oils; updates referenced standard for testing thereof (Box 129, Folder 30)
      - HB 2447 (09) Influenza vaccination; requires Board of Health to develop and issue guidelines for administration (Box 129, Folder 31)
      - HB 2449 (09) Infectious disease; establishes deemed consent to test for HIV and hepatitis B and C and release result (Box 129, Folder 32)
      - HB 2453 (09) Electronic prescribing; Secretary of Health and Human Services, etc. to establish a website (Box 129, Folder 33)
      - HB 2454 (09) Uniform Commercial Code; financing statements (Box 129, Folder 34)
      - HB 2456 (09) Tobacco Settlement Foundation; changes name to Virginia Foundation for Healthy Youth (Box 129, Folder 35)
      - HB 2458 (09) Posting of charity care policies; requires hospitals to post information related thereto (Box 129, Folder 36)
      - HB 2459 (09) Right to notify; consumer in mental health facility to have opportunity thereto of his condition (Box 129, Folder 37)
      - HB 2460 (09) Transportation of person under emergency custody, etc.; allowed to be transported by family member (Box 129, Folder 38)
      - HB 2461 (09) Notification of family member in commitment process; disclosure of certain information of patient (Box 129, Folder 39)
      - HB 2462 (09) Patient level data system; reporting requirement (Box 129, Folder 40)
      - HB 2464 (09) Higher educational institutions, certain; management agreements with State (Box 129, Folder 41)
      - HB 2465 (09) Removal of public official; no person who signs petition for removal of shall be liable for costs (Box 130, Folder 1)
      - HB 2467 (09) Life insurance; funding preneed funeral contracts (Box 130, Folder 2)
      - HB 2472 (09) Short-term rental property; definition/removes daily rental property define. from merchants' capital (Box 130, Folder 3)
      - HB 2473 (09) Public use; term to include public libraries for purposes to prohibit loitering on grounds (Box 130, Folder 4)
      - HB 2474 (09) Planning time for school teachers; Superintendent to ensure elementary school teachers are provided (Box 130, Folder 5)
      - HB 2476 (09) HOV lanes; extend sunset provision allowing those vehicles bearing clean special fuel license plate (Box 130, Folder 6)
      - HB 2477 (09) Popes Head Road; designating as State byway in Fairfax County (Box 130, Folder 7)
      - HB 2479 (09) Real property tax rate; reduces tax imposed on commercial property in Northern Virginia (Box 130, Folder 8)
      - HB 2480 (09) Real property tax; commercial property in Northern Virginia and Hampton Roads (Box 130, Folder 9)
      - HB 2482 (09) Prescription donation; clarifies hospital and clinic may redispense donation medication to indigent (Box 130, Folder 10)
      - HB 2485 (09) Vehicle safety inspections; codifies exceptions thereto set forth in proclamation of July 2006 (Box 130, Folder 11)
      - HB 2486 (09) Emergency custody; authority of law-enforcement officer (Box 130, Folder 12)
      - HB 2487 (09) Library aid; period in which transition of city to town status may continue to receive (Box 130, Folder 13)
      - HB 2491 (09) Charter; City of Galax (Box 130, Folder 14)
      - HB 2494 (09) Charter; City of Hopewell (Box 130, Folder 15)
      - HB 2495 (09) Child labor; permits children 17 years of age satisfying enumerated criteria to drive automobiles (Box 130, Folder 16)
      - HB 2499 (09) Aerospace Advisory Council; adds Director of Space Grant Consortium to serve as ex officio (Box 130, Folder 17)
      - HB 2500 (09) 'A Place of My Own' Program; Department of Social Services to develop (Box 130, Folder 18)
      - HB 2502 (09) Transient occupancy tax; adds representatives of lodging properties to local tourism organizations (Box 130, Folder 19)
      - HB 2504 (09) Income tax, corporate; real estate investment trusts (Box 130, Folder 20)
      - HB 2505 (09) Towing and recovery licensure; extends date which a person needs valid license from Board (Box 130, Folder 21)
      - HB 2506 (09) Energy efficiency programs; investor-owned electric utilities to recover costs of designing, etc. (Box 130, Folder 22)
      - HB 2507 (09) Fishing licenses; Marine Resources Commission to issue refunds on prorated basis (Box 130, Folder 23)
      - HB 2513 (09) Mob violence; adds act of violence to listing of offenses reported by juvenile intake officer (Box 130, Folder 24)
      - HB 2515 (09) Workers' Compensation Act; increases maximum tax rate that may be assessed on uninsured, etc. (Box 130, Folder 25)
      - HB 2517 (09) Standards of Learning; directs Board of Education provide option of industry certification, etc. (Box 130, Folder 26)
      - HB 2519 (09) Electric utilities; SCC to establish procedures regarding refunds of moneys collected (Box 130, Folder 27)
      - HB 2523 (09) Alcoholic beverage control; grounds for suspension or revocation of a license (Box 130, Folder 28)
      - HB 2524 (09) Personal property tax; classification (Box 130, Folder 29)
      - HB 2528 (09) Disposition of firearms; no participation in program if individuals are given valuable in exchange (Box 130, Folder 30)
      - HB 2529 (09) National Defense Industrial Authority; adds Secretary of Commerce and Trade to board of directors (Box 130, Folder 31)
      - HB 2531 (09) Electricity; SCC to conduct proceeding to determine appropriate energy conservation, etc. (Box 130, Folder 32)
      - HB 2532 (09) Reimbursement of expenses in DUI incidents; locality entitled to restitution from person convicted (Box 130, Folder 33)
      - HB 2533 (09) Studded tires; emergency vehicles to operate therewith (Box 130, Folder 34)
      - HB 2534 (09) License plates, special; issuance to veterans of Operation Enduring Freedom, etc. (Box 130, Folder 35)
      - HB 2537 (09) Special education; definition of a parent to make decisions relating thereto (Box 130, Folder 36)
      - HB 2539 (09) Enterprise Applications, Division of; established within VITA, appoint Chief Applications Officer (Box 130, Folder 37)
      - HB 2541 (09) Criminal records checks; required for licensure to practice as real estate licensees (Box 130, Folder 38)
      - HB 2544 (09) Election recounts; losing candidate may initiate when difference less than 5% of total vote cast (Box 131, Folder 1)
      - HB 2545 (09) Aquarium and Marine Science Center; adds to list of organizations to receive contributions (Box 131, Folder 2)
      - HB 2546 (09) Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation; America's 400th Anniversary Commemoration, report (Box 131, Folder 3)
      - HB 2549 (09) College Savings Plan; exclusion of certain financial records from Freedom of Information Act, etc. (Box 131, Folder 4)
      - HB 2550 (09) Economic development; incentive financing for major employment and investment projects, report (Box 131, Folder 5)
      - HB 2551 (09) Onsite treatment works; provides specific requirements therefor designed by professional engineer (Box 131, Folder 6)
      - HB 2557 (09) Health insurance plan, State; coverages and benefits (Box 131, Folder 7)
      - HB 2558 (09) Biosolids permit; if amended to increase acreage by 50% more than initial permit give public notice (Box 131, Folder 8)
      - HB 2559 (09) Homestead exemption; increases for householders who are 65 years of age or older (Box 131, Folder 9)
      - HB 2560 (09) Homestead exemption; increased for veterans (Box 131, Folder 10)
      - HB 2565 (09) Farmland Preservation, Office of; to provide technical assistance to local governments interested (Box 131, Folder 11)
      - HB 2566 (09) Purchase of land by Department of Forestry; used for nonstate forest purposes (Box 131, Folder 12)
      - HB 2568 (09) Consumer Real Estate Settlement Protection Act; disclosures (Box 131, Folder 13)
      - HB 2569 (09) Manufactured Housing Licensing and Transaction Recovery Fund Law; limits amount of actual damages (Box 131, Folder 14)
      - HB 2571 (09) Restricted driver's license; court to provide during period of suspension (Box 131, Folder 15)
      - HB 2575 (09) Income tax, corporate; extends sunset date of major business facility job tax credit (Box 131, Folder 16)
      - HB 2576 (09) Solid waste; electricity generated therefrom (Box 131, Folder 17)
      - HB 2577 (09) Highway noise abatement; Transportation Board or VDOT to plan therefor when constructing (Box 131, Folder 18)
      - HB 2578 (09) Novelty cigarette lighters; prohibiting purchase to persons under age of 18 (Box 131, Folder 19)
      - HB 2580 (09) Illegal immigrants; removes Code provision that prohibits an arrest thereof more frequently (Box 131, Folder 20)
      - HB 2582 (09) Charter; Town of Clarksville (Box 131, Folder 21)
      - HB 2583 (09) Local government investment pool; limitations (Box 131, Folder 22)
      - HB 2586 (09) Sandbridge Beach Subdivision; Board to determine which structures, etc., are in imminent danger (Box 131, Folder 23)
      - HB 2589 (09) Students; assessment of those limited English proficient (Box 131, Folder 24)
      - HB 2592 (09) Electric vehicles; creates separate class of property tax for rate purposes (Box 131, Folder 25)
      - HB 2594 (09) Vietnam Human Rights Day (Box 131, Folder 26)
      - HB 2595 (09) Charitable gaming; raises permit exemption threshold for volunteer fire department or rescue squad (Box 131, Folder 27)
      - HB 2596 (09) Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority; amends Compact relating to Board membership, etc. (Box 131, Folder 28)
      - HB 2597 (09) Alcoholic beverage control; ABC Board to adopt regulation that require off-premise retail licensees (Box 131, Folder 29)
      - HB 2599 (09) Real Estate Cooperative Act; amendment of declaration, revival of expired declarant rights (Box 131, Folder 30)
      - HB 2602 (09) Conservation and Recreation, Department of; power to establish non-competitively procured contracts (Box 131, Folder 31)
      - HB 2604 (09) Racing Commission; advance deposit account wagering (Box 131, Folder 32)
      - HB 2607 (09) Communications sales and use tax; distributions to Bath County and Town of Clifton (Box 131, Folder 33)
      - HB 2612 (09) Emergency response plans; ensuring victims' rights (Box 131, Folder 34)
      - HB 2615 (09) Public Procurement Act; increases amount for single or term contracts for professional services (Box 131, Folder 35)
      - HB 2618 (09) Interagency Dispute Resolution Advisory Council; membership terms (Box 131, Folder 36)
      - HB 2619 (09) Transfer students; credits earned for online courses taken in Virtual Virginia program to transfer (Box 131, Folder 37)
      - HB 2623 (09) Multijurisdiction grand jury; jurisdiction to include investigation of trademark infringement (Box 131, Folder 38)
      - HB 2624 (09) Central Va. Criminal Justice Acad.; may enter into agreemt. to train private correctional personnel (Box 131, Folder 39)
      - HB 2626 (09) Line of Duty Act; investigation of claims by police departments and sheriffs offices (Box 131, Folder 40)
      - HB 2627 (09) Alcoholic beverage control; unlawful possession, affirmative defense (Box 131, Folder 41)
      - HB 2629 (09) Antifreeze bittering agent; engine coolant, etc., manufactured after Jan. 1, 2011, must contain (Box 131, Folder 42)
      - HB 2636 (09) Hunting and fishing; special license for youth groups (Box 131, Folder 43)
      - HB 2637 (09) Arrests; requires fingerprints be taken and forwarded to Central Criminal Records Exchange (Box 132, Folder 1)
      - HB 2638 (09) Capital murder; add auxiliary police officer, etc. to definition of law-enforcement officer statute (Box 132, Folder 2)
      - HB 2639 (09) Freedom of Information Act; exempts certain records of Department of Veterans Services, etc. (Box 132, Folder 3)
      - HB 2642 (09) Elections; verification of registered voter lists (Box 132, Folder 4)
      - HB 2643 (09) Economic development entities; extension of performance agreements (Box 132, Folder 5)
      - HB 2644 (09) Locksmiths; certain exempt from certification if employed by licensed private security business (Box 132, Folder 6)
      - HB 2646 (09) Betterment loans; established, eligibility therefor to repair, etc., failing onsite sewage systems (Box 132, Folder 7)
      - HB 2651 (09) Real property tax; sale of tax-delinquent property (Box 132, Folder 8)
      - HB 2655 (09) Accident and sickness claim proceeds; provider services rendered outside of State (Box 132, Folder 9)
      - HB 2656 (09) School for Deaf, Blind, and Multi-Disabled; Bd. of Ed., etc., hold in abeyance conveyance thereof (Box 132, Folder 10)
      - HB 2660 (09) Capital outlay plan; constitutes State's six-year proposal for projects (Box 132, Folder 11)
      - HB 2663 (09) Water and waste authorities; appointment of industrial or economic development authority directors (Box 132, Folder 12)
      - HB 2665 (09) Broadband Infrastructure Loan Fund; created (Box 132, Folder 13)
      - HB 2666 (09) Elections; authorizes candidate representatives to observe part of election day, no assisting voter (Box 132, Folder 14)
      - HB 2671 (09) Cabin Capital of Virginia; designating Page County thereas (Box 132, Folder 15)
      - HB 2672 (09) Minority Business Enterprise, Dept. of; definitions to include individual who is U.S. citizen, etc. (Box 132, Folder 16)
      - HB 2673 (09) Investment Partnership Act; amends definition of 'eligible company.' (Box 132, Folder 17)
      - HB 2674 (09) Mental Retardation Waiver and IFDDS Waiver; Governor to plan to eliminate urgent care waiting lists (Box 132, Folder 18)
  - 2009 Special I Session
    - House of Delegates
      - HB 5007 (09) Evidence, testimonial; procedure notifying defendant of introduction of certificate of analysis. (Box 170, Folder 2)
      - HB 5008 (09) Claims; Arthur Lee Whitfield. (Box 170, Folder 3)
  - 2009 Regular Session
    - Senate
      - SB 39 (09) Traffic accident reports; increases amount of damage threshold to be reported by law enforcement (Box 132, Folder 19)
      - SB 802 (09) Holland-Councill Memorial Bridge; designating as Route 58 bridge over Blackwater River (Box 132, Folder 20)
      - SB 806 (09) Nonresident decedents' personal property in State; transferor thereof may comply with law of state (Box 132, Folder 21)
      - SB 808 (09) Foreign service officers of U.S.; provides certain requirements in suits for divorce and annulment (Box 132, Folder 22)
      - SB 811 (09) Elevator mechanics, certified; Board for Contractors shall extend time for compliance for certain (Box 132, Folder 23)
      - SB 817 (09) License plates, special; issuance to members and supporters of various organizations (Box 132, Folder 24)
      - SB 823 (09) Transportation of person under emergency custody, etc.; allowed to be transported by family member (Box 132, Folder 25)
      - SB 827 (09) Family life education; adds benefits, etc., of marriage for men, etc., to list of topics covered (Box 132, Folder 26)
      - SB 833 (09) Notaries public; electronic notarization to be developed by Secretary of Commonwealth, etc. (Box 132, Folder 27)
      - SB 834 (09) Public Procurement Act; procurement of architectural and professional engineering service for project (Box 132, Folder 28)
      - SB 837 (09) State Law Library; authorized users (Box 132, Folder 29)
      - SB 845 (09) Livable home tax credit; increase limit on or after January 1, 2010 (Box 132, Folder 30)
      - SB 848 (09) Elections; clarifications and revisions to registration and election processes (Box 132, Folder 31)
      - SB 851 (09) Higher Educational Institutions Bond Act of 2009; created (Box 132, Folder 32)
      - SB 852 (09) Parking Facilities Bond Act of 2009; created (Box 132, Folder 33)
      - SB 855 (09) Uniform Power of Attorney Act; created (Box 132, Folder 34)
      - SB 857 (09) Charter; Town of Blacksburg (Box 132, Folder 35)
      - SB 858 (09) Transient occupancy tax; Giles County may impose at rate not to exceed 5% to promote tourism (Box 132, Folder 36)
      - SB 860 (09) Income tax credit, earned; employers to provide notice to employees that may be eligible (Box 132, Folder 37)
      - SB 865 (09) Coal combustion by-products; use, reuse, or reclamation in a flood plain. (Box 132, Folder 38)
      - SB 868 (09) Retail Sales and Use Tax; expands definition of public facility for purpose of using certain revenues. (Box 132, Folder 39)
      - SB 869 (09) Charter; City of Fredericksburg. (Box 132, Folder 40)
      - SB 871 (09) Health, Department of; relieves Department of its responsibility of certain reports. (Box 132, Folder 41)
      - SB 877 (09) Law-enforcement officers, retired; meets training and qualification standards to carry weapon. (Box 132, Folder 42)
      - SB 878 (09) Massage Therapy, Advisory Board on; created. (Box 132, Folder 43)
      - SB 881 (09) Grass; adds Stafford County to counties authorized to require property owners to cut. (Box 133, Folder 1)
      - SB 882 (09) Parking; regulation thereof of watercraft, boat trailers, etc., in certain counties. (Box 133, Folder 2)
      - SB 883 (09) Charter; Town of Warsaw. (Box 133, Folder 3)
      - SB 884 (09) Banking institutions; reclassification or conversion of shares of stock. (Box 133, Folder 4)
      - SB 886 (09) Elevator mechanics; Board of Contractors to delegate certification in event of emergency. (Box 133, Folder 5)
      - SB 888 (09) Deed of trust; assignment of penalty for failure to release. (Box 133, Folder 6)
      - SB 889 (09) Ignition interlock; operation of motor vehicle without, penalty. (Box 133, Folder 7)
      - SB 890 (09) Motor vehicles; collection of court costs. (Box 133, Folder 8)
      - SB 891 (09) Communications sales and use tax; distributions to Bath County and Town of Clifton. (Box 133, Folder 9)
      - SB 892 (09) Information technology projects; Governor to include a biennial appropriation therefor. (Box 133, Folder 10)